<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Nooraizad Zailani</title>
        <link>https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Nooraizad Zailani</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 01:23:37 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts on Master of Data Science, University of Malaya</title>
            <link>https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/post04/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 01:23:37 +0800</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/post04/</guid>
            <description>I have completed my Master of Data Science at the University of Malaya (UM). I finished them in 2 years. It was one hell of a journey and a memory that I will cherish for the rest of my life. In this post, i would like to share my opinion on the course and whether it is worth recommending. In the first section of this post, I would be giving an overview of the program, and why did I choose to study data science.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have completed my Master of Data Science at the University of Malaya (UM). I finished them in 2 years. It was one hell of a journey and a memory that I will cherish for the rest of my life. In this post, i would like to share my opinion on the course and whether it is worth recommending. In the first section of this post, I would be giving an overview of the program, and why did I choose to study data science. Then, I would elaborate on things I learn during the course and bits of advice I would give to someone considering moving into data science.</p>

<p> <strong>Overview of the program</strong></p>

<p> This course is offered under the Faculty of Computer Science and Information Technology. Students are required to complete a total of 42 credit hours with a distribution of 24 credit hours for core courses, 8 credit hours for the elective courses and remaining 10 credit hours for data science research project. This course is a coursework mode program. It is a full-time mode with classes held weekdays from 6 pm to 9 pm. Students are flexible in selecting how many courses they want to take. This courses aimed to equip the student with knowledge and skills of data analysis in terms of big data and methodology in data science.</p>

<p>For each subject, there are 14 weeks of classes, 1 week of revision week and final examination. There are tutorials, quizzes, mid-semester examination and the final examination. However, the arrangement is depending on the lecturer of each course. Students are graded based on the score of carry marks throughout the semester and the score for the final examination. The proportion is usually 60% carry marks and 40% for the final exam. Students are required to score at least a B grade or forced to retake the paper (at the time of writing). The course plan is as below:
 <br />
<br />
<em>Core Subjects</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Research Methodology<br /></li>
<li>Principles of Data Science<br /></li>
<li>Data Analytics<br /></li>
<li>Programming for Data Science<br /></li>
<li>Data Mining<br /></li>
<li>Machine Learning for Data Science<br /></li>
<li>Big Data Management<br /></li>
<li>Data Science Research Project
 
<br /></li>
</ul>

<p><em>Elective Subjects (Student are required to choose any 2 subjects from the list below)</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Parallel and Distributed Programming</li>
<li>Big Data Applications and Analytics</li>
<li>Network and Security</li>
<li>Numerical Optimization
 <br /></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Why did I choose to study data science</strong><br />
 <br />
I am a mathematics graduate. I obtained my Bachelor of Science in Mathematics from the University of Technology MARA (UiTM) in June 2017. At that time, to be honest, I am not sure what kind of position or role that interests me. During my degree studies, I took accounting courses and also fundamentals of programming in c++ along with core courses being mathematics and statistics related courses such as algebra, calculus, ordinary differential equation, real analysis and mathematical modelling. I have done my internship at Gamuda Berhad in the finance department. With experience obtained during my internship, I am more incline to look into finance and management position.\ 
 <br />
I stumbled upon a job advertising for a graduate in the mathematics field. The company is a multinational company with business in information technology consulting. I applied to the position and after several interview session, finally able to land the job as a programmer analyst. Together with the other 11 graduates, we are the second batch of Malaysian graduate. I am very thankful for his opportunity. With my background in mathematics and statistic, I have been placed in the analytic and information management team. In the first two months of employment, they have provided us with training and classes. This opportunity helped me to learn and understand things I never learn before. For example, SQL, database and data warehousing concept, and soft skills required in the working environment, especially in a client facing environment.<br />
 <br />
After the training program, I have been assigned to a data visualization project for a client in the banking industry. The project duration is about 8 months, and we have been tasked to develop some dashboard to the clients and business users. The tools or software that we used is Tableau. Soon, I developed an interest in big data and data science. I am fascinated by how we can utilize the data that we have and help us make decisions. Data visualization is one of the critical element in data science. Having involved in the project exposed me on communications skills and how we can present our findings to the client and business users. This experience thought me how to deal with business users, how to present my findings and also challenges working in a fast-paced environment.<br />
<br />
Then I started to read on data science and data analytics. It turned out that we are not fully utilize the data that we have around us. There is much application of data analytics ranging from data engineering, data visualization, and sophisticated machine learning. At that time, you can see the terms data science almost everywhere. Companies and organizations are looking into data science as it can help the organization to solve their problem and avoid making the same mistake. Soon, I found out that local universities have started offering their master degree in data science. After some research, I have decided to pursue a master in data science at the University of Malaya.<br />
 <br />
<strong>What did I learn in the course</strong><br />
 <br />
This course covered the students on various data science techniques and methodologies. Principles of Data Science introduce students to the concept of data science, multiple methods, advantages and disadvantages of particular data science techniques and also discussed what is big data as an overview. In Programming for Data Science subjects, students are being introduced to R Programming. Subjects like Data Mining, Data Analytics and Big Data Management discuss techniques dealing with data including but not limited to data cleaning, data storing and algorithms that can be used to process those data. Machine Learning for Data Science teaches the student on the concept of machine learning, from the basic machine learning algorithm to the sophisticated algorithm.</p>

<p>Research Methodology subject helped the student to prepare for their final submission of Data Science Research Project. This subject explores many aspects of research writing, from research methodology, thesis writing and process involves throughout the research project. For elective subjects, I have selected Parallel and Distributed Programming and Big Data Applications and Analytics. Parallel and Distributed Programming is a bit challenging for me. The course required the student to have a basic understanding of computer science. Topics like Parallel and Distributed System Model, Process, Threading and Communication between Process and also Computer Cluster for Scale Computing are very new to me and required extra effort to understand the concept and relates them to data science. Nevertheless, I enjoyed the learning process, and we able to get our hands dirty during the lab session. For instance, we need to set up our own distributed file-sharing system and create a virtual machine on the cloud.</p>

<p><strong>The advice I would give to someone considering moving into data science</strong></p>

<p>I must say that I&rsquo;ve learnt a lot during my time as a student of master of data science. Not only during the class session, but the opportunity to meet professional from different fields is something new. I meet up with fellow coursemate from engineering background, finance, banking, bio-health, software developer and of course, fresh graduates are there too. During group assignment, for instance, we will talk and discuss with each other. Everyone has a different opinion, and it makes the interaction exciting and informative. This is one of the things you can benefit from joining this course. You will have the opportunity to build your network there.\ </p>

<p>We also got the chance to work on different kind of datasets and get the hear opinion from people working in the field related to the domain of the dataset. It&rsquo;s always exciting to listen to a different point of view when starting to analyze or work on a dataset.</p>

<p>If you do not have programming or computer science background, in my opinion, you can still do well in this course. The Introduction to Programming for Data Science course is adequate to introduce students to the basic concept in programming. But I do suggest for the student to work on a personal project related to data science such as data cleaning task, data visualization or machine learning project and get familiar with R or Python. Kaggle is one of the best places to start. There are many datasets you can find there, and you can also browse notebook to get ideas on how to approach a problem.<br />
<br />
Having a background in mathematics, statistics and probability will also help you to excel in this master degree background. Subjects such as Machine Learning for Data Science introduce students to numbers of algorithms. Understand how these algorithm work will help you to explain the concept better and also if you wish to improve and enhance your model when implementing machine learning analysis. I suggest for the student without mathematics and statistics background to do self-learning on these topics. I recommend video from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xxpc-HPKN28&amp;list=PLWKjhJtqVAblQe2CCWqV4Zy3LY01Z8aF1&amp;index=5&amp;t=1s">freecodecamp.org</a> that teaches statistics needed in data science. The video is well made and explained every concept in details.<br />
<br />
In conclusion, this course provides student on the techniques and skills needed for them to prepare for a role as a data scientist. But I do believe a few things can be improved. I recommend for the university to invite data scientist or data engineer for a talk on their day to day task, how they get into data science and challenges they faced during their work. This can be very helpful to students and give them a bit of overview of how data scientist works in the real world.</p>

<p>I believed time to time other improvements can be made for this course. As the course is still new, students need to be proactive themselves in exploring and learning data science techniques. It would be beneficial to take own initiative and get hands dirty.</p>

<p>I have fun doing this master degree. I got to know new friends and have the opportunity to work alongside them. Lecturers are very helpful and always open to ideas and suggestions. Having completed this program, I learnt so many things and looking forward to applying all these things in my career. </p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Of Faisal Tehrani, the Hardy Boys and the Dancing Men</title>
            <link>https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/post03/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 13:52:21 +0800</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/post03/</guid>
            <description>A good friend of mine, Dr Syameem Raub wrote a post about books that got him hooked on reading. In his post, he mentioned that when we were together in a boarding school, I lend him my The Da Vinci Code written by Dan Brown. He described how he got into reading after being impressed with the book&amp;rsquo;s storyline, structure, plot and the elements of surprises presented by the author. Indeed The Da Vinci Code is a well-written book.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A good friend of mine, Dr Syameem Raub wrote a <a href="https://drsyameem.com/the-first-book-that-got-me-hooked-on-reading/">post</a> about books that got him hooked on reading. In his post, he mentioned that when we were together in a boarding school, I lend him my The Da Vinci Code written by Dan Brown. He described how he got into reading after being impressed with the book&rsquo;s storyline, structure, plot and the elements of surprises presented by the author. Indeed The Da Vinci Code is a well-written book. I enjoyed reading it too. You can never guess how is the ending going to be. Dr Syameem remarked how I seem unimpressed with the book. Well, I like the book, but at that time, I already immersed myself with novels and short stories written by Faisal Tehrani.</p>

<p>The first book, written by him that I read is 1515. It is a fiction book. I remember a bit about the plot. There are two point of view if i am not mistaken. The first POV tells a story of how Malacca is lead by a woman named Tun Nyemah Mulya during the invasion of Portugal. Faisal wrote on the Kingdom of Malacca, their glory and struggles during that time. Another POV is the modern-day woman named Mulya, and I cannot forget the details if she is the descendant of Tun Nyemah Mulya or not. But I do remember how I enjoyed reading this novel. The way Faisal presented different POV from a different time and still able to tell a good story. It is a fiction, but after finished reading it, I am wondering if it is a true story, hidden to us?</p>

<p>I can say for sure that reading is not one of my hobbies. But I do enjoy reading. When I was a kid, I read a lot of Ladybird&rsquo;s Key Words with Peter and Jane. My mum asked my siblings and me to read it. Children can get to improve their English, recognise the alphabet, increase their vocabulary and in the same time enjoy a good story. Then I start to read on a few teenagers novel and stories such as Nancy Drew and The Hardy Boys. It was quite popular during the days, and there is also Malay translated version. I think I read both versions. Then Harry Potter came. Everyone starts to read it. I read the whole volume but stopped at the Goblet of Fire. Then I lose interest in the storyline. I don&rsquo;t know, maybe it just me.</p>

<p>When I started my higher upper secondary school, I get to know Faisal Tehrani. I remember I bought almost every book written by him. Like I mentioned, I liked 1515, and other titles that I enjoyed are Detektif Indigo series, 1415H, and Bedar Sukma Bisu. Then I started to learn guitar. I play a lot and also jamming with some of my friends. Reading seems to lose its ability to interest me anymore. I only read articles on the web, newspaper or some magazine about music.</p>

<p>During my foundation year at the University of Malaya, I still listen and play music, and play football and rugby. But I get to know Sherlock Holmes from watching the Sherlock Holmes movie released in 2009. I remember how Dr Syameem and I always talked about the film. We discussed a lot of the plot and spoke about how we will change the ending, for example, if we can make Irene Adler role bigger in the movie or the Secret Intelligence Service is the mastermind. We even make a list of quotes from the film. Then I bought a complete collection of novels and short stories of Sherlock Holmes. I can clearly remember my favourite short story: The Adventure of the Dancing Men. I felt like I have fallen in love again with reading. Then I borrowed the Lord of the Rings from my friend.</p>

<p>But as years passed by, the reading seems to lose its way again. With other commitments, I could not commit to reading as frequent as I like. But seeing Dr Syameem, now I want to start reading. We talked about an idea of a fiction novel, and I know I need to start reading again before I can commit to this project. I do not know if I would be addicted to buying books like Dr Syameem, but slowly I will pick up this good habit again.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>COVID-19 Dashboard</title>
            <link>https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/post02/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 15:22:17 +0800</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/post02/</guid>
            <description>Hi everyone. I have created a simple and straightforward Tableau dashboard about COVID-19. The dashboard focuses on Malaysia data, but there is an overview of worldwide cases. The dashboard can be access here. The dashboard consists of two pages, the first page showing a world map with tooltips displaying the number of cases, deaths and recovered in each country. At the top of the map, there is the information of total cases, total deaths and total recovered worldwide.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone. I have created a simple and straightforward Tableau dashboard about COVID-19. The dashboard focuses on Malaysia data, but there is an overview of worldwide cases. The dashboard can be access <a href="https://public.tableau.com/views/Covid19Dashboard_15860728590360/Dashboard1?:display_count=y&amp;:origin=viz_share_link">here</a>. The dashboard consists of two pages, the first page showing a world map with tooltips displaying the number of cases, deaths and recovered in each country. At the top of the map, there is the information of total cases, total deaths and total recovered worldwide. Below the map, there is a table with countries, cases, deaths and recovered cases. There is also a filter by country, to filter the page to get single or multiple countries.</p>

<p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nooraizad/nooraizad.github.io/master/covid1.png" alt="Page 1" title="Page 1" /></p>

<p>The next page of the dashboard focussing on Malaysia COVID-19 cases. Like the first page, there is a map of Malaysia. By hovering into different states, users can see the number of cases, deaths and recovered in each state. There are 3 line charts daily of total case, deaths and recovered in Malaysia. From this chart, we can observe the daily numbers of each case in Malaysia. Then, we have a table of state, total case, total death and mortality rate for each state. The mortality rate is defined as the number of death in a population. It is calculated from the number of death divided by the number of cases of COVID-19. Users can sort the table by clicking at the header name. </p>

<p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nooraizad/nooraizad.github.io/master/covid2.png" alt="Page 2" title="Page 2" /></p>

<p>On data collection, I am using python with BeautifulSoup package to crawl data from <a href="https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus/ and">https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus/ and</a> stored them in a csv file. For data on Malaysia cases, I crawled the data from various sites such as <a href="https://www.outbreak.my/ and ">https://www.outbreak.my/ and </a><a href="https://www.thestar.com.my/news/nation/2020/03/23/covid-19-current-situation-in-malaysia-updated-daily">https://www.thestar.com.my/news/nation/2020/03/23/covid-19-current-situation-in-malaysia-updated-daily</a>. The code can be found here <a href="https://github.com/nooraizad/Basic-Web-Scrapper">https://github.com/nooraizad/Basic-Web-Scrapper</a>. The csv files later will be used at Tableau to create the visualisation. </p>

<p>For data refresh, I run the script daily. The script is run every day at 9:00 pm Malaysian time. I am looking method to run the script automatically, and then the data source will be consumed by Tableau automatically. Based on my findings, I can achieve this by setting up a pipeline in Azure Data Factory, host my Python script there and setup a schedule so that the pipeline will be run daily. I will be starting to explore Azure Data Factory and will share the findings. 
The dashboard that I have created is simple and straightforward. But I believed it has the critical measurement that we would like to know about the COVID-19. I might add more features and measurement in the future. Any idea and suggestion are welcome. </p>

<p>Kaggle is hosting COVID-19 Open Research Dataset Challenge. The competition challenge data scientist to provide meaningful insight about COVID-19. I think every data scientist should join the competition and contribute to the community on the findings. Together, we fight this pandemic by staying at home and play our role as a data scientist to help provide results and insight that will be beneficial to everyone. I am joining the competition and will be sharing my findings in my future post.</p>

<p>Until next time, cheers.
 </p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hello world!</title>
            <link>https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/post01/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 23:02:04 +0800</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://nooraizad.github.io/posts/post01/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to nooraizad.com. My name is Muhammad Nooraizad. In this blog, I will be writing about data science, data analysis, personal project, my interest and personal lives. However, the content here will be focusing on data science as I have a deep interest in it. I enjoyed derive meaningful insight from data and presented the findings to the audience. Data science is an exciting field, and it keeps evolving every day as we are speaking.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to nooraizad.com. My name is Muhammad Nooraizad. In this blog, I will be writing about data science, data analysis, personal project, my interest and personal lives. However, the content here will be focusing on data science as I have a deep interest in it. I enjoyed derive meaningful insight from data and presented the findings to the audience. Data science is an exciting field, and it keeps evolving every day as we are speaking. We can see many application of data science that helped us to solve real life problem. I will be sharing my works here, hoping it can be beneficial to readers and also for me to keep track things I have learned.</p>

<p>I am based in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia and working in the information technology sector. I enjoyed reading fantasy genre novels, watching Netflix and spending my time with my family. I used to play Dota 2 a lot. Nowadays, I am not able to play as much as I wanted due to time limitation and now I enjoyed watching Dota 2 tournament.</p>

<p>I am looking forward to connect with readers.</p>

<p>Cheers</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
